Previously on Transformers: Prime
在上一集里
The Cons are back,
虎子们回来了
Cliff might be knee deep in scrap.
飞过山处境非常危险
Cliffjumper's life signal... just went offline.
飞过山的生命信号…刚刚消失了
As of today, only we five Autobots remain on this earth.
时至今日 地球上只剩下我们五个汽车人了
What are they?
他们是什么？
Talking cars that turn into robots,
会说话的车变的机器人
or the other way around.
或者机器人变的车
Look, you maybe in danger
听着 你可能有危险
because you are one of the few,
因为你看到了我们
one of the only who have ever seen us.
很少有人知道我们的存在
Why are you here?
你们为什么来地球？
To protect your planet from Megatron.
保护你们的星球免受威震天的侵害
But if his return is imminent,
但如果他即将东山再起
it could be catastrophic.
又要掀起一场腥风血雨
I have returned!
我回来了！
Of the energon deposits we have located while you're away, Lord Megatron,
威震天陛下 您不在之时 我们发现了数个能量矿
this one is by far the most significant.
而这个矿的储备简直是取之不竭
The drones have been mining without a pause during your absence,
这段时间 机械兵一直在不停地采矿
and have amassed quite a stock pile.
库存量尤为可观
You there, fetch me a sample.
来人啊 给我拿个样本！
Starscream.
红蜘蛛！
Now that I have returned,
既然我已经回来了
I will issue the commands.
就该由我发号施令
I¡­ understand, Lord Megatron.
我…明白 威震天陛下
Then as your humble servant,
作为您的忠实奴仆
shall I ready the Space Bridge
我随时准备启动太空桥
to bring forth the Decepticon army you have surely gathered during your three years in space?
迎接这三年来 您在太空组建的霸天虎军队
My army will come.
我的军队会来的
But my time away has yielded a more...
但我在太空漂流时
intriguing means of materializing them,
找到一种能够增强实力的神秘方法
the solidified form of the matter the ancient techs refer to
这种物质的液体形态
as the blood of the Unicron.
在古代资料中被称为――宇宙大帝之血
Unicron the Destroyer.
“毁灭者”宇宙大帝
But it is said that his blood is the anti-spark.
但据说他的血液跟火种不兼容
Plucked from cosmic shores, gaze upon Dark Energon.
“采于宇宙之滨 将得黑暗能量”！
Legend tells that it holds the power to... revive the dead.
传说它威力无比 甚至能…起死回生
We require only cadaver to be certain.
我们需要找具尸体来试试看
Are you willing to make the ultimate sacrifice?
你愿意做出巨大牺牲吗？
That may not be necessary.
这个我看没必要
If I may, Lord Megatron.
请允许我 威震天陛下
Consider it a welcome-home present.
就当是为您的回归献上的贺礼
And since you now know of our existence,
既然你们发现了我们
I fear that as of the last night,
照昨晚的事情来看
the Decepticons know of yours.
恐怕霸天虎是不会放过你们的
Got it, if we spot any strange vehicles, call 911.
明白 如果看到任何不明车辆 立刻报警
Can we go now?
我们可以走了吗？
Are you insane?
你疯了吗？
I'm living a dream here in Botswana,
这儿对我来说就像天堂一样
and I will now allow you or anyone else to shatter it.
你们谁都别想破坏我的美梦！
It is best that you three remain under our watch.
你们三个最好接受我们的监护
At least until we can determine our enemy's intentions.
起码我们要弄清楚 敌人有什么意图
Optimus, with all due respect,
擎天柱 恕我直言
the human children are in as much danger here as anywhere.
无论在这里还是别处 这些孩子都同样危险
Children?
小孩子？
They have no protective shell!
他们没有防护罩！
If they get underfoot, they will go¡­ squish.
如果不小心被踩到 他们就…扁了
Then for the time being, Ratchet,
那么从现在起 救护车
we must watch where we step.
我们必须走一步 看一步
What's that?
那是什么？
Proximity sensor.
近程传感器
Someone's up top.
有人在上面
It's Agent Fowler.
是福勒探员
I thought we were the only humans who know about you guys.
我们不是唯一知道你们的人类吗？
Special Agent Fowler is our designated liaison to the outside world.
特派员福勒是我们和外界之间的特别联络人
As he tends to visit only when there're issues.
他来找我们 一定有要事发生
It maybe best if you did not meet him at this time.
你们最好暂时先别和他见面
Seven wrecks, thirty-four fender benders,
七辆车被毁 三十四起剐蹭事故
a three hour traffic jam,
三小时交通堵塞
and a particular note:
还有一条特别消息
numerous reports of a speeding motorcycle of unknown make,
多家媒体报道 发现一辆不明车型的高速摩托
and a black & yellow custom muscle car.
和一辆黄黑条纹的肌肉车
So, anything you care to get off your tin chest, Prime?
那么 你有什么心里话要说吗 擎天柱？
We have the situation under control, Agent Fowler.
情况尚在我们控制之下 福勒探员
They're back, aren't they?
他们回来了 是吧？
If you're referring to the Decepticons,
如果你指的是霸天虎
I have doubts that they ever left.
我怀疑他们从未离开过
Your planet is much too valuable.
你们的星球太有开发价值了
Then it's time to wake up the Pentagon.
那我现在就要通知五角大楼
Hear me, Agent Fowler.
听我说 福勒探员
We're your best,
如果和霸天虎对抗
Says you.
别太自负
Hey, fleshy.
嘿 肉条
Did anyone get spattered on that freeway?
有人血溅高速公路吗？
Team Prime knows when to use force,
领袖卫队知道什么时候该用武力
and how much to use.
出手的轻重我们心中有数
Bulkhead, I needed that!
隔板 那个我还有用呐！
Enough!
够了！
Military involvement will only result in catastrophe.
军队的干涉只会导致更大的灾难
Perhaps you can condone wide spread human casualties, Agent Fowler.
或许你可以接受人类尸横遍野 福勒探员
I, however, cannot.
但我 决不能接受
Then do us both a favour and handle this, Prime,
那就为我们双方的利益着想 擎天柱
under the radar.
做得…干净点儿
Or I will.
要么让我来
Pretty big bearings¡­
不自量力
for a human.
区区一个人类而已
Agent Fowler has concerns for his world, Bulkhead,
福勒探员担心的是他的世界 隔板
as he should be.
这是他的职责
Let us see if power born of darkness
看看源自黑暗的力量
can reignite the spark.
能否重燃火种
That's your plan?
那就是你的计划？！
Bring Autobots back from the dead to attack us?
复活死掉的汽车人 让我们挨揍？
That is no longer an Autobot.
那已经不再是个汽车人了
Just a mindless beast,
只是个没有意识的猛兽
it's only instinct to destroy anything in its path.
它唯一的本能就是 摧毁挡在路上的一切
There, Starscream,
看吧 红蜘蛛
rise the indestructible seed of my army, the ultimate weapon¡­
我无坚不摧的军队已经上路 这终极武器…
once I learn to control it.
一旦被我掌握 将会大发神威
Blast that earth tech!
该死的地球科技！
Cliffjumper's signal pop back online.
飞过山的信号又出现了
Who's Cliffjumper?
飞过山是谁？
How is that possible?
怎么可能？
It isn't.
当然不可能
Another bug.
又出故障了
The system is chock-full of them.
系统故障一大堆
If there's any chance Cliff's alive?
飞过山有没有可能还活着？
Ratchet, prepare sick bay.
救护车 准备医务室
We may need it.
可能用得上
what can we do?
我们能做点什么？
Remain with Ratchet.
和救护车留守
Autobots, roll out!
汽车人 出发！
What just happened?
刚才是怎么回事？
I transported them to the designated coordinates via the Ground Bridge.
我用环陆桥把他们送到了特定的坐标地点
What's a Ground Bridge?
环陆桥是什么？
Since we don't currently possess the means or the energon required for inter-galactic travel.
因为我们现在没有星际旅行需要的设备和能量
You're stuck here¡­
你们被困在…
on earth?
地球上了？
With the likes of you, yes.
和你们困在一起 是的
But I constructed the Ground Bridge
但我建造了环陆桥
to enable travel from here to anywhere on your planet.
可以到达你们星球的任何角落
Naturally.
当然能
You mean I could just
你是说
shoot on over and visit my parents in Tokyo?
我这么一跳 就能到东京去看我的父母吗？
Within moments.
眨眼工夫
In fact, allow me to send you there immediately, all three of you.
这样吧 我马上把你们三个都送过去
Watch it, Ratchet.
说话当心 救护车
Energon mine.
能量矿
Judging by its scale,
照这个规模来看
the Decepticons have been tunneling here for quite some time.
霸天虎应该已经开采过一段时间了
Let's find Cliffjumper.
我们去找飞过山！
What is this, anyway?
这是什么玩意儿？
Broken, don't touch.
坏了 别碰
Don't touch that either.
那个也别碰
So is there anything we can touch?
有什么东西是我们可以碰的吗？
How come you guys are using human computers?
你们干嘛要用人类的计算机？
It certainly isn't by choice.
我们别无选择
It was handed down from the previous talents
我们当时接管了这个导弹发射井
when we inherited this former missile silo.
这是那些天才留下的
I made modifications as I see fit.
我根据需要做了一些调整
I think I can fix that.
我想我能把故障修好
Really?
真的吗？
You know this is complex technology, don't you?
这是超级复杂的科技 知不知道？
I mean it isn't a child's toy.
这可不是儿童玩具！
Now try.
现在试试
Maximum overdrive!
全速冲击！
What an operation.
全不费功夫
Blood of Unicron.
宇宙大帝之血
How might I fathom the depth of your mystery,
我如何才能揭开你的奥秘
become worthy of wielding your astonishing power.
并得以支配你那惊人的力量？
Lord Megatron, intruders have been detected in the mines.
威震天陛下 矿场出现入侵者
Optimus?
擎天柱？
Indeed.
就是他
I need more time to prepare on appropriate reception for my old friend.
我还需要时间
Ready the ship for departure.
启动飞船 准备撤离
But the energon I've mined...
可我挖到的那些能量
the Autobots will sieze it!
会被汽车人抢走的！
Then blow the mines!
那就把矿炸掉！
It's Cliff. I have a visual.
是飞过山 我看到了
We'll cover you, go!
我们掩护你 上吧！
Cliff!
飞过山！
Let's get you home, partner!
我们回家吧 搭档！
Prime!
擎天柱！
I'd stick around, but I'm squeamish.
我也想留下 但我有点洁癖
The drone is gonna blow!
要爆炸了！
Autobots, roll out!
汽车人 出发！
Ratchet, bridge us back.
救护车 把我们传送回去
Use the arrival coordinates,
使用目的地坐标
now!
快！
Cutting it a little bit close.
千钧一发啊
How about Cliffjumper?
飞过山怎么样了？
What was that explosion?
那爆炸是怎么回事？
Was there a fight?
你们打架了吗？
Can we come with next time?
下次我们能去吗？
Look!
听着！
Hey, hey, Miko.
嘿 嘿 神子
Let's go see what the bots hide in their sock drawers.
我们去看看 他们的抽屉里有什么宝贝
Seriously?
真的假的？
Arcee, what did you see?
阿尔茜 你看到什么了？
Not Cliff.
不是飞过山
At least... not anymore.
起码…现在不是了
He was mutated, butchered,
他被改变了 被分尸
like something from those Con experiments during the war.
像大战时虎子做的试验那样
I'm fine, just dizzy.
我没事 只是有点晕
Robots who get dizzy?
机器人也会头晕？
Robots with emotions?
机器人也会难过？
Robots... who can die?
机器人也会死？
What is this?
这是什么？
Don't know.
不知道
Cliff was covered in it,
飞过山浑身上下都是
leaking it.
还流了出来
Go take a decontamination bath, now.
马上去洗个净化澡 快
Optimus, I hate to bug, but... no bars.
擎天柱  我不想打扰你 但…这儿没信号
A security precaution.
这是安全措施
The silo walls isolate all radio waves.
发射井的墙壁阻断了所有无线电波
Well, if I don't call my mom like now,
如果我现在不打电话给我妈妈
I'm pretty sure the cops will be out looking for me.
我敢肯定 警察会开始找我的
Have you broken the law?
你犯过法吗？
Oh, curfew,
噢 是宵禁
it's after 10pm.
已经晚上十点多了
I'd better get home, too,
我也该回家了
or I'll be grounded for a year.
否则我一年都别想出门
Earth customs,
地球风俗
I hadn't considered.
是我考虑不周
But the issue of your safety remains.
但还是要保证你们的安全
Bulkhead, accompany Miko home.
隔板 送神子回家
Awesome! My host parents will freak!
太棒了！吓死我的监护人！
And maintain covert surveillance in vehicle form.
保持伪装形态进行监视
Curbside duty, got it.
在路边望风 明白
Bumblebee, you'll watch over Raf.
大黄蜂 你来照顾拉夫
Ratchet...
救护车…
Busy!
忙着呢！
Arcee, you'll accompany Jack.
阿尔茜 你护送杰克
Oh, still dizzy.
噢 我还是晕
You're fine, says your physician.
医生说你没事了
Arcee, I just wanted to say,
阿尔茜 我只想说
I'm really sorry for your loss.
对于你的损失 我真的很遗憾
What could you possibly know about loss?
你能理解什么叫损失吗？
What? You think you're the only one with problems?
怎么？你以为只有你才有心事吗？
I'm not sure girl-trouble counts!
泡妞失败算什么心事！
I'm pretty sure my girl-trouble started the night I met you.
我敢说 我泡妞失败 正因为那晚碰见了你
Cons!
虎子！
No! Mom.
不！是我妈
Jack?
杰克？
Mom! Don't freak, I can explain.
妈妈！别激动 我可以解释
Can you?
你能吗？
Jackson Darby, we've talked about this.
杰克逊・达比 我们已经谈过这个了
I know, and...
我知道 那个…
You don't know.
你不懂
I worred about you enough when you were not here.
你不知道 你不在家时 我已经够担心了
Now I have to worry about you driving a motorcycle?
我现在还要担心你骑摩托出事吗？
I'm sixteen.
我已经十六岁了
I can't be riding a ten speed forever.
不可能永远骑十变速自行车
How did you even afford this?
你哪来的钱买这个？
It's used.
是二手货
It's abused, really,
挺破的 真的
needs a ton of repairs.
需要大修
But the point is...
但其实…
I may have been a kid when I bought this,
买头盔的时候 我还是小孩
but I'm not anymore.
但我已经长大了
You always tell me to make responsible choices.
你经常教育我 做选择要负责任
Well, I chose her.
现在 我选择了她
And I'll be responsible.
我会负责的
I promise.
我发誓
"Her"?
“她”？
I don't think you could be bringing girls home just yet.
我觉得你还不能把女孩子带回家过夜
I'd... like to think she brought me.
我…觉得是她带我回来的
Well, I'm glad you finally have a reason to wear your helmet,
好吧 很高兴你终于有理由戴头盔了
every single time you ride.
每次骑车都要戴！
You... will take me for a spin every once in a while?
你得先跟我打招呼才行
We'll see.
看情况吧
She's kind a temperamental.
她的脾气不太好
Shhh, are you crazy?
嘘 你疯了吗？
You'll wake up my mom!
会吵醒我妈妈的！
Grab your helmet, it's go time.
去拿头盔 是时候上路了
Oh... It's Saturday!
今天是星期六啊！
You can watch cartoons back at base with Bumblebee.
你可以在基地陪大黄蜂看动画片
Cartoons? I'm sixteen.
动画片…我都十六岁了
And leave a note for your mom. She worries.
留个纸条给你妈妈 不然她会担心的
I don't think you need to worry further Autobot interference, master.
我看您不必再担心汽车人的骚扰了 主人
Not with Optimus gone.
擎天柱已经完蛋了
And what evidence do you possess of this fact?
你说这话有什么证据吗？
I destroyed the mines,
我炸掉了矿场
as you instructed.
按您的指示
Optimus is not so easily destroyed.
消灭擎天柱没那么容易
We have millennia worth of battles behind this to prove it.
我们之间千万年的战斗就可以证明
Maybe you should take a break, my Lord.
或许您该休整一下 陛下
I worry that too much contact with the Dark Energon
我担心 过度和黑暗能量接触
might allow its properties to adversely affect you.
会对您产生某种…负面影响
Or perhaps, Starscream,
其实 红蜘蛛
I have not permitted myself contact enough!
我可能还没接触够呢！
Wait! Lord Megatron, no!
等等！威震天陛下 不！
Not your spark chamber!
别拿您的火种室冒险！
You do not know what it will do!
您不知道会有什么后果！
The base elements of this goo are like nothing I've ever encountered.
这种粘液的基本元素 我从没见过
It must be extremely concentrated
阿尔茜的症状发展迅速
to have affected Arcee so rapidly.
说明它一定是高度浓缩的
Unfortunately,
可惜
complete results are slow coming
缺少合适的诊断工具
without the use of proper diagnostic tools.
完整分析慢得要死
Thank you very much, Bulkhead!
全都怪你 隔板！